准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
睡觉时间
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
该睡觉了  小蜗
Time for bed, Gary
小蜗
Gary
俗话说得好
You know what they say
好奇心害死蜗牛
curiosity salted the snail
千万别被迷了眼  你这小蜗牛
Mind your wandering eye, you little mollusk
祝你做个好梦  小蜗
Sweet dreams, Gary
在这
Over here
等下
Wait a minute
我还没有驾照
I don't have a driver's license
裤头村驾照
海绵宝宝
我的驾照
My driver's license
真不敢相信
I can't believe it
我照片拍得可真好看
I sure take a good picture
道路尽头
真是的
Darn
早知道就留胡子了
I should have grown a moustache
我怎么能忘掉最重要的交规
how could I have forgotten
the most important rule of driving?
一定要系好安全带
Always wear your seatbelt
蟹堡王
这里可以看到蟹堡王
I can see the Krusty Krab from here
泡芙老师  你看
Mrs. Puff, look
我终于有驾照了
I finally got my driver's license
你就算做梦也不能领驾照  海绵宝宝
Not even in your dreams, Mr. SquarePants
不要
No
我在哪
Where am I?
那是我吗
Is that me?
还是这个是我
Or is this me?
我还在做梦吗
Am I still dreaming?
这个肯定是小蜗的梦
This must be Gary's dream
我要进去看一看
I'm going to get a closer look
看看这些书啊
Look at all these books
不知道小蜗在哪
I wonder where Gary is
小蜗
Gary
请问一下  先生
Excuse me, sir
你有没有看见
Have you seen
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
小蜗
Gary?
你竟敢侵犯我纯洁的梦境
How dare you invade the sanctity of my dreams
小蜗
Gary
你原来会说话
You can talk
尘世的限制无法束缚梦中的个体
In dreams, one is not tethered by earthly limitations
什么意思
What does that mean?
过来
Come
长久以来  人们认为梦
For ages, dreams have been thought of
是通向另一个世界的窗口
as windows to another realm
梦境甚完美
"Let me not mar that perfect dream
莫让晨曦玷
"by an auroral stain
每夜皆修整
"but so adjust my daily night
方能再出现
that it may come again"
这是艾米莉迪金森写的
Emily Dickinson wrote that
谁
Who?
这首你应该比较熟悉
Here's one you might know
[ 爱德华·利尔所作的打油诗 ]
从前有个秘鲁人
"There once was a man from Peru
梦见吃鞋入了神
"who dreamed he was eating his shoe
半夜梦中惊坐起
"He woke with a fright in the middle of the night
发现梦居然成真
to find that his dream had come true"
小蜗  你好聪明
Gee, Gary, you sure are smart
你以为我壳里都是装热气的吗
Did you think my shell was full of hot air?
感谢你的教导  小蜗
Well, thanks for the info, Gary
我要回到我自己的梦里去了
I'm going back to my own dream now
千万别被迷了眼  你这小海绵
Beware of your wandering eye, you little poriferan
不知道派大星在做什么梦
I wonder what Patrick's dreaming
我忍不住就是要看
I can't resist
派大星
Hey, Patrick
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
派大星  这是个梦
You know, Patrick, this is a dream
你想做什么都可以
You can do anything you want
对
Yep
随便什么都行
I mean anything
看好了
Watch
我可以变成摩天大楼
I can turn into a skyscraper
变高
Going up
我可以变出
I can make
一百万个我
a million of me
没错
Yup
可真是
Tartar sauce
我要到别人的梦里去了
I'm going to a different dream
好
Okay
再见  海绵宝宝
Bye, SpongeBob
该死
Shoot
我就只剩那个两毛五硬币了
That was my last quarter
这回肯定会特别的好
This is going to be good
章鱼哥
Squidward
Hey, Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你怎么不吹下去了  莫章特
Why do you stop playing, Wolfgang Amadeus Tentacles?
[ 改自奥地利作曲家莫扎特 ]
遵命  陛下
Yes, Your Highness
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我没有命令过你要停下来
I have not instructed you to stop
快给我吹
Now, play
再跟我讲点那个秘鲁人的故事
Do tell me the one about the man from Peru again
海绵
Sponge
宝宝
Bob
朕是来这聆听美妙乐曲的
I came here to hear beautiful music
要是听不到  你的头就跟它一个下场
If I don't get my wish, it'll be your head
章鱼哥
Squidward
没
No
门
way
我求你了  海绵宝宝
Please, SpongeBob
不准耍花招
No tricks
相信我吧  章鱼哥
Trust me, Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你为何停止吹奏那美妙的音乐了
Why have you stopped playing that wonderful music?
其仙乐动我心脾
His music touches me ever so
热泪盈眶青衫湿
l fear that my tears might stain my petticoat
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you
美食车
这发出曼妙乐声的是何种乐器
What is this instrument
that produces such lovely sound?
再见了  章鱼哥
So long, Squidward
我到珊迪家了
I'm at Sandy's
看着就挺酷
This looks neat
不知
I wonder
海绵宝宝  什么风把你给吹来了
Hey, SpongeBob, what brings you here?
珊迪
Hey, Sandy
这是怎么一回事
What's going on?
这是在114000英尺的高空自由落体
Well, we're free-falling from 114,000 feet
要降落到那个很小的目标点上去
and we're going to land on that itty-bitty target
好像有点危险
This seems kind of dangerous
只要有个降落伞就行了
Not as long as you got a big, old parachute
好的
Okay
不是鞋子  海绵宝宝
Not "pair of shoes," SpongeBob
[ 引号内容互相谐音 ]
是降落伞
"para-chute"
明白
Got you
不是鹦鹉
Not a "parakeet"
是降落
para
蛤蜊粪
医生
Medic
别闹了
All right, that's it
不要再去捣乱别人的梦了
No more messing with people's dreams
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
Mr. Krabs?
你好啊  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
珍珍  原来这是你的梦
Pearl, this is your dream
你刚好赶上我的茶会
You're just in time for the tea party
其实我是在找你爸的梦
Actually, I was looking for your dad's dream
他在隔壁
He's next door
男生就是不懂茶会有多优雅
Boys don't understand
the sophistication of tea parties
对吧  毛绒玩具先生
Right, Mr. Stuffy?
再见
Bye
蟹老板的梦肯定会更阳刚
I bet Mr. Krabs' dream will be more robust
终于逮到你了  滑头恶魔
I got you now, you slippery demon
你跟我斗的劲儿还挺大
You're putting up a good fight
大得很哪你
Yes, you are
你在干什么  蟹老板
What you doing, Mr. Krabs?
我在扒海神王的口袋
I'm picking Neptune's pocket
你这是在说什么
What are you talking about?
就那个冰冷坚硬  翻来覆去的现金
l'm talking about cold, hard, flipping cash
也就是大白钱莫比刀乐
It's the mighty Moby dollar
[ 改自白鲸莫比·迪克 ]
看见它了没  小子
Do you see her, boy?
我逮到它了
I got her
它来了
here she comes
它喷钱了
Thar she blows
蟹老板你看
Look, Mr. Krabs
是硬币
Pennies
不用管这点零钱了  小子
Never mind the small change, lad
拿网来
Get the net
是这个吗
This one?
错了错了错了  是捕钱网
No, no, no, no, no, the money net
就在我屁股口袋里
It's in me back pocket
你长小胡子的样子可真帅  蟹老板
You look real good with a moustache, Mr. Krabs
裤头村驾照
蟹老板
那东西不关你事  小子
Never mind that, boy
把网准备好
Ready the net
网准备好了  先生
Net ready, sir
成功了
I did it
我终于抓到了
I-I finally did it
恭喜你了  蟹老板
Congratulations, Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝  不要
No, SpongeBob
别把它给放走了
Don't let it go
海绵宝宝  快抓
Get it, SpongeBob
快抓  快抓
get it, get it
回来
Come back
不要
No
这事一定会名垂野史的对吧  蟹老板
This'll make a great fish story, eh, Mr. Krabs?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
怎么了  蟹老板
Yes, Mr. Krabs?
你被开除了
You're fired
发 射
海之霸
痞老板梦见裤头村了
Plankton's dreaming about Bikini Bottom
我杀
Zap
看见你了
I see you
我杀
Zap
我的腿
My leg
看见你了
I see you
我杀
Zap
痞老板
Plankton
看见你了
I see you
我杀
Zap
蟹堡王
看啊  是蟹堡王
Oh, look, it's the Krusty Krab
蟹黄堡之家
home of the Krabby Patty
我踩
Crush
我舔
Lick, lick
这就不是什么正经梦
This isn't a dream
这就一噩梦
This is a nightmare
小蜗
Gary
不要
No
过来  小猫猫
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty
小蜗
Gary
我护住你了  小蜗
I've got you, Gary
快藏好
Peekaboo
我脚来了
Here comes my foot
好
Yeah
看来他抓住重点了
l think he's got the point
我应该是有得解释了
Well, I guess I've got some explaining to do, huh?
别别别
No, no, no
别踩脸
No, not the face
好玩归好玩
That was fun and all
不过还是回自己的梦乡里好
but it's good to be back in my own dream cloud
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你们想把我怎么了
What do you want from me?
快走开
Leave me alone
海绵宝宝  海绵宝宝
SpongeBob, SpongeBob
别别别别
No, no, no, no
别过来
stop
你们都穿睡衣来干什么
What are y'all doing in your pajamas?
是在办睡衣派对吗
Are we having a slumber party?
才不是  我们没在办睡衣派对
No, we are not having a slumber party
行行好了  海绵宝宝
Do us all a favor, SpongeBob
别来搞我们的梦了
and stay out of our dreams
滚远点
Take a hike
白天跟你一起还不够受的吗
Don't we get enough of you during the day?
谁有两毛五硬币
Does anyone have a quarter?
肥皂泡
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
在下蟹黄堡雨
It's raining Krabby Patties
好耶
Yeah
吃点宵夜然后再回去睡觉
A quick midnight snack, and then it's back to bed
小蜗
好好睡吧  我的小天使
Sleep tight, my little angel
海花生酱
拿到了
Here it is
海花生酱配水母酱三明治吃
Nothing like a sea-nut butter
and jellyfish jelly sandwich
最能助眠了
to help you get to sleep
冰箱
The fridge
小蜗  我感觉不太对劲
Gary, I don't feel like myself
别傻了  小蜗
Don't be silly, Gary
我才没得感冒
I don't get colds
得的是肥皂泡病
I get the suds
不对  小蜗
No, Gary
得肥皂泡病就会有泡泡冒出来
If I had the suds, I'd have bubbles coming out of me
我不能得肥皂泡病
I can't get the suds
因为这样会害我误工
because then I'll have to miss work
放屁  小蜗
No, Gary
我就是喜欢这样穿内裤
l like wearing my underwear like this
我没病
I'm not sick
我要去上班
I'm going to work
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝  蟹黄堡怎么做得这么慢
SpongeBob, what's holding up those patties?
马上就好  老板
Right away, sir
海绵宝宝  你这是怎么了
SpongeBob, what's wrong with you?
你脸色可是苍白得不得了啊
You're paler than a baby sea horse
肥皂泡病
The suds?
你要的蟹黄堡来了  蟹老板
Here's that patty you wanted, Mr. Krabs, sir
海绵宝宝  你病得不能再上班了
All right, SpongeBob, you're too sick to work
不行  蟹老板
No, Mr. Krabs
我没事  真的
I'm okay, honest
不行  快回家休息去
No, now go home and get some rest
不是在针对你  小子
Nothing personal, lad
我可不能让你把喷嚏打在食物上
I just can't have you sneezing all over my food
我的腿
My leg
别  等等
No, wait
别走
Wait
小蜗
Gary
我好难受
I feel horrible
我逗谁呢  小蜗
Who am I kidding, Gary?
我得肥皂泡病了  毫无疑问
I've got the suds, no doubt about it
最好先处理好  免得病情失控了
l better take care of this before it gets out of hand
喂
Hello
珊迪  我病了
Sandy, I'm sick
能送我去看医生吗
Can you escort me to the doctor's?
好啊  海绵宝宝
Sure, SpongeBob
我到你那会快得不得了的
l'll be there faster than a barefoot jackrabbit
on a hot greasy griddle in the middle of August
珊迪  谢谢
Okay, Sandy, thanks
来了
Coming
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
这是去滑雪吗
Going skiing?
我病了  派大星
I'm sick, Patrick
要去看医生
I'm going to the doctor
什么
What?
不能去
You can't go
为什么  派大星
Why not, Patrick?
我认识的一个人认识的一个人
I know a guy who knows a guy
从前去看过一次医生
who went to the doctor once
门诊部可是超级可怕的地方
and the doctor's office is a horrible, horrible place
肯定没肥皂泡病可怕
It can't be as horrible as the suds
真的很可怕  海绵宝宝
It is, SpongeBob
首先  他们会让你坐进
Well, first they make you sit in the
候诊室
waiting room
就这段可怕吗  派大星
Is that the horrible part, Patrick?
不对  之后更可怕
No, it gets worse
他们会让你看旧杂志
They make you read old magazines
然后医生就会拿出听诊器
Then the doctor pulls out his stethoscope
不会吧
No
没错
Yes
那个设备特别邪恶
It's a device so sinister
又特别冰冷  一旦触碰到你的肉体
so icy cold, when it touches your bare flesh
就会
it
不要
No
不要听诊器
No stethoscope
不要医生
No doctor
不要旧杂志
No old magazines
不要
No
派大星  我不想去看医生了
Patrick, I don't want to go the doctor
这才对
Exactly
帮我康复过来吧  派大星
You got to help me get better, Patrick
求你了
Please?
当我医生好不好  派大星
Would you like to be my doctor, Patrick?
不然朋友还能干嘛
What else are friends for?
看来必须要把这些洞堵住
It appears as though we'll have to plug up these holes
这样应该就能成
This ought to do the trick
看吧
Voilà
舒服点了没
Feel better?
不清楚
I don't know
救命  我缩小了
Help, I'm shrinking
不要
No
求你不要伤害我
Please, don't hurt me
泡泡没了
No bubbles
派大星  你的治疗有效
Patrick, your treatment is working
真的吗
You think so?
没错
Sure
照这样下去  我马上就能被治好了
At this rate I'll be cured in no time
我该要打电话找珊迪
In fact, I'm going to call Sandy
叫她不用过来了
and tell her not to come
谢了  派大星医生
Thanks, Dr. Patrick
别人都说我成事不足败事有余呢
And they said I'd never make anything out of myself
我手指太大  不方便按按钮了
My fingers are too big for the buttons
派大星医生  能帮我打给珊迪吗
Dr. Patrick, could you call Sandy for me?
好啊  海绵宝宝病人
Sure, patient SpongeBob
喂  珊迪
Hello, Sandy?
喂  派大星
Hiya, Patrick
我代表我病人海绵宝宝给你打电话
I'm calling on behalf of my patient, SpongeBob
我在送他去医院的路上
I'm on my way over to take him to the hospital
那玩意再也用不着了
That will no longer be required
他今天由我来照顾
He is in my care as of today
我就过来瞧一眼
Well, I'm coming over to take a look
我到这来会快得不得了的
I'll be over there faster
than a barefoot jackrabbit on a hot
对对  不得了
Yeah, yeah, the rabbit
别来烦我  珊迪
Don't bother, Sandy
海绵宝宝快点
SpongeBob, quick
珊迪要来了
Sandy's coming
必须确认你已经康复了
We've got to make sure you're well
不然她就会带你去看医生
or she'll take you to the doctor
不准碰我  我无菌
Don't touch me, I'm sterile
手术刀
Scalpel, please
海花生酱
舒服点没
Feeling better?
舒服点了没
Felling better yet?
不太行
Not really
那
How
现在
about
呢
now?
我觉得
I don't
没有
think so
舒服点没
Feeling better?
没
No
那现在呢
How about now?
没
Nope
那现在呢
How about now?
在吗  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
珊迪来了
It's Sandy
没有人在家
There's no one home
派大星  把这扇门打开
Patrick, you open this door
派大星  有时候我就是搞不懂你
Patrick, sometimes I just don't understand you
派大星  海绵宝宝呢
Okay, Patrick, where's SpongeBob?
他这会儿不在
He's not here at the moment
请在哔声后留言
Please leave a message after the beep
行了  你告诉我
Okay, now, tell me
你什么时候开始有两座房子的
Since when do you have two houses?
从我没地方放东西那会开始的
Since I ran out of space to put my stuff
不错
Yep
你家房子什么时候开始长脚的
Since when does your house have feet?
这是我家房车
This is my mobile home
嗨  珊迪
Hiya, Sandy
看来泥土疗法很有效
The dirt therapy seems to be working just fine
派大星  海绵宝宝必须要去看真医生
Patrick, SpongeBob has to see a real doctor
用不着
No, he doesn't
我把他照顾得可好了
I'm taking good care of him
给人家瞧瞧  海绵宝宝
Show her, SpongeBob
说  啊
Say "ah"
看见没
See?
他比我想的还要严重
He's even worse than I thought
你几个意思
What do you mean?
他好得很
He's fine
我真没事  珊迪
I'm okay, Sandy, really
我马上就带你去看医生
I'm taking you to the doctor right now
那是我的病人
That's my patient
不准带他去看医生
You can't take him to the doctor's
别给我傻了  派大星
Don't be silly, Patrick
他是我的
He's mine
海绵宝宝  你马上就能康复过来的
SpongeBob, you'll be better soon
我会救你的
I'll save you
我康康康康康康复了  真的
I'm ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-better, guys, really
看你干的什么好事  派大星
Now look what you've done, Patrick
什么好事
What I've done?
你一出来事情就全乱套了
Everything was fine until you showed up
你非法行医  迟早会被逮捕
You should be arrested for impersonating a doctor
我可是个好医生
I'm a good doctor
对吧  海绵宝宝
Right, SpongeBob?
没错
Right
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
我停不下来
I can't stop now
救命
Help me
亮晶晶的硬币
Shiny dimes
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
快停下  海绵宝宝
Stop, SpongeBob
停下
Stop
医院
急诊
海绵宝宝先生  看来你得了肥皂泡病
Well, Mr. SquarePants, it seems you have the suds
准备好接受治疗了吗
Are you ready for your treatment?
你该不会要我看旧杂志吧
You're not going to make me read old magazines, are you?
不会的  笨蛋
No, silly
你要接受海绵疗法
you get the sponge treatment
汉斯快来
Oh, Hans
好耶
Yeah
好痒啊
This tickles
我又能闻到味了
I can smell again
好耶
Yeah
我感觉焕然一新
I feel as good as new
我爱医生
I love the doctor
这是你的棒棒糖
Here's your lollipop
还有棒棒糖吗
A lollipop?
医生  我也得肥皂泡病了
Hey, Doc, I got the suds, too
好的  派大星医生
Oh, yes, Dr. Patrick
我们给你准备了特殊的疗法
We have a special treatment for you
等下
Wait
好疼
That hurts
等等
Wait
事情好像不对劲
This doesn't seem right